Maine Acadian Cultural Survey Collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Guides to the Collections in the Archive of Folk Culture
Maine Acadian Cultural Survey Collection 1991
AFC 1991/029
American Folklife Center
National Park Service
8,016 items.
8 containers: 2,800 manuscript materials.
32 sound cassettes: analog.
7 sound tape reels: analog, 7 1/2 ips; 7 in.
ca. 5,080 photographs: color, black and white
ca. 50 drawings.
5 videocassettes of 5 (VHS).
42 disks.
Archive of Folk Culture, American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Collection consists of sound and video recordings, photographs, manuscript materials, printed materials, correspondence, field notes, and administrative files documenting folklife--including architecture, music, dance, storytelling, material culture, and occupational culture--in the Upper Saint John River Valley on the Maine and New Brunswick border.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Bayley, Julie; Brassieur, C. Ray; Marshall, Howard W.; Ornstein, Lisa; Taylor, David Alan, 1951-; Whitman, David A., 1950-
Organizations
American Folklife Center; Archive of Folk Culture (Library of Congress); United States. National Park Service. North Atlantic Regional Office
Subjects
Acadians--Maine--Folklore.; Acadians--Maine--Social life and customs.; Acadians--New Brunswick--Folklore.; Acadians--New Brunswick--Social life and customs.; Catholics--Maine--Social life and customs.; Folk music--Maine.; Franco-Americans--Maine--Folklore.; Franco-Americans--Maine--Social life and customs.; French-Canadians--New Brunswick--Folklore.; French-Canadians--New Brunswick--Social life and customs.; Vernacular architecture--Maine.
Places
Acadia National Park (Me.); Saint John River Valley (Me. and N.B.)--Social life and customs.
Titles
Acadian cultural survey; Maine Acadian cultural survey project; Maine Acadian cultural survey.
Form/Genre
Drawings.; Ethnography.; Field notes.; Field recordings.; Interviews.; Manuscripts.; Oral histories.; Photographs.; Recipes.; Sound recordings.; Video recordings.
Arrangement
Organized by format into the following series: 1. Manuscript materials; 2. Sound recordings; 3. Graphic materials; 4. Moving images.
Acquisition
The Maine Acadian Cultural Survey Collection was the result of Maine Acadian Cultural Survey Project, an eight-week study conducted in 1991 as a joint project of the American Folklife Center and the North Atlantic Regional Office of the National Park Service to research information to be used in planning an Acadian Cultural Center in Maine.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Related Material
Copies of the collection are also available in the Acadian Archives / Archives acadiennes at the University of Maine at Fort Kent.
Access and Restrictions
Duplication of the collection materials may be governed by copyright and other restrictions. Access restrictions apply; some or all content may be stored offsite. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Online Content
Part of the Maine Acadian Cultural Survey Collection is available on the Library of Congress Web site at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/afconline.afc1991029.
Scope and Content
The Maine Acadian Cultural Survey Project was conducted in 1991 as a joint project of the American Folklife Center and the North Atlantic Regional Office of the National Park Service. In 1990 the U.S. Congress passed the Maine Acadian Culture Preservation Act (P.L.101-543), mandating that a study of Acadian culture in Maine be conducted for the purpose of providing data to be used in planning an Acadian Cultural Center in Maine. As a result of this act, the Park Service invited the Center to join them in undertaking such a study. The Maine Acadian Cultural Survey Project is the fifth major collaborative project between the Park Service and the Center, and the design and execution of the project were largely based on knowledge gained through earlier projects.
Under the terms of the cooperative agreement between the Park Service and the Center, the Center developed and administered a study of Acadian culture in Maine, produced a draft report with findings of the study and recommendations for future research and cultural programming, and provided the Park Service with a reference copy of the field data.
Eight weeks of field research by five researchers, interviewing residents and documenting aspects of traditional culture in context, in the St. John Valley yielded an ethnographic collection consisting of 5,081 photographic images, 3,600 pages of print materials, fieldnotes, manuscripts and catalogs, 42 computer discs, 40 hours of audio recordings, 50 pages of sketches, and an assortment of ephemeral material. These data were used to compile a 199-page report, titled The Maine Acadian Cultural Survey, that was submitted to the National Park Service. The report contains the findings of the survey of Acadian culture in Maine as well as recommendations for the development of a Maine Acadian Cultural Center. Following a review by National Park Service officials, the report was published by the Park Service and submitted to Congress, and is expected to be used as a planning document by the Maine Acadian Culture Preservation Commission.
The ethnographic collection of the project has been added to the Archive of Folk Culture, Library of Congress. A reference copy of the collection was donated to the Archive acadiennes at the University of Maine at Fort Kent, where it is readily available to the residents of the study area.
The project also proved to be a successful vehicle for creating or strengthening ties between the Center and cultural agencies and individual researchers in Maine. Project personnel worked closely with the Archives acadiennes, the Maine Arts Commission, the Maine Historic Preservation Commission, the Northeast Archives of Folklore and Oral History, and the University of Maine at Fort Kent. In addition, researchers had considerable contact with a large number of local historical societies and other cultural organizations based in the study area.
Container List
- Series 1: Manuscript materials
  - Collection finding aid (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cooperative Agreement (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Agreement between American Folklife Center and National Park Service. Draft of agreement and signed final agreement, with related correspondence. 27 pp.
  - Maine Acadian Culture Preservation Commission (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Various documents. 52 pp.
  - P.L. 101-543, The Maine Acadian Culture Preservation Act (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Drafts of the act; testimony for and against; legislative history. 186 pp. and two copies of enacted bill.
  - Acadian scholars: potential contacts (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Prepared by David Taylor. 13 pp.
  - American Folklife Center Board of Trustees (Box 1, Folder 6)
    May 7, 1991, memo from David Taylor about survey of Acadian cultural resources in Maine. 2 pp.
  - Ancelet, Barry Jean (University of Southwestern Louisiana) (Box 1, Folder 7)
    January 29, 1991, letter from David Taylor. 1 p.
  - Belous, Robert (National Park Service) (Box 1, Folder 8)
    January 30, 1991, letter from David Taylor. 1 p.
  - Bibliographies concerning Acadians in North America (Box 1, Folder 9)
    75 pp.
  - Biographical Data Form (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Blank copies. 3 pp.
  - Brassieur, C. Ray (University of Missouri) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Letters to and from Brassieur, C. Ray; publications. 22 pp. and two publications.
  - Budget and timetable for field survey (Box 1, Folder 12)
    34 pp.
  - Calendar of Annual Events in the Upper Saint John Valley (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Compiled by Lisa Ornstein and Julie Bayley. 36 pp.
  - Certificate of appreciation (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Blank copies of certificate sent to project informants. 12 pp.
  - Consent forms (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Master copies of three types. 3 pp.
  - Consent forms (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Forms signed by informants. 33 pp. All contents have been moved to case files.
  - Contacts (Box 1, Folder 17)
    List of individuals and institutions with information about Acadians in Maine. Compiled by Camila Bryce-Laporte. 8 pp.
  - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Miscellaneous. 11 pp.
  - Documentation guide for project fieldworkers (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Prepared by David Taylor. 42 pp.
  - Dubay, Guy (Madawaska, Maine) (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Letter from David Taylor. 1 p.
  - Dumont, Richard (University of Maine at Fort Kent) (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Letters from Alan Jabbour. 2 pp.
  - Equipment (Box 1, Folder 22)
    List of documentation equipment used during field survey. 3 pp.
  - Expenses (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Preliminary accounting of expenses. Invoices, purchase orders, and other documents. 133 pp. Purchase orders have been moved to case files.
  - Final Evaluation (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Assessment of the Maine Acadian Cultural Survey Project, by David Taylor. Report and executive summary for AFC Board of Trustees. 28 pp.
  - Hand-outs (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Hand-outs, in French and English, about the field survey. 14 pp.
  - Hart, Judy (National Park Service) (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Letters from David Taylor. 2 pp.
  - Human Resources List (Box 2, Folder 27)
    Contacts in the St. John Valley, arranged by categories. Prepared by Lisa Ornstein. 14 pp.
  - Income (Box 2, Folder 28)
    Documents concerning transfer of funds from the National Park Service to the Library of Congress. 3 pp.
  - Informants, letters from (Box 2, Folder 29)
    Letters from project informants to David Taylor. 8 pp.
  - Informants, letters to (Box 2, Folder 30)
    Thank you letters to informants from David Taylor. 94 pp.
  - Ives, Edward D. (Box 2, Folder 31)
    2 pp.
  - Jabbour, Alan (Box 2, Folder 32)
    Letter to Bruce Jacobson; letter from Bruce Jacobson. 32 pp.
  - Jacobson, Bruce (National Park Service) (Box 2, Folder 33)
    Letters to and from Bruce Jacobson. 66 pp.
  - Kominski, John (Library of Congress) (Box 2, Folder 34)
    Memos and other documents from Alan Jabbour concerning cooperative agreement with NPS. 7 pp.
  - LeBlanc, Bernard (University of Moncton) (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Letters from David Taylor; letters to David Taylor; other documents. 35 pp.
  - Mailing list (Box 2, Folder 36)
    Project mailing list. 9 pp.
  - Maine Arts Commission (Box 2, Folder 37)
    Letters to Maine Arts Commission from David Taylor; documents from the Commission concerning Acadians in Maine. 5 pp. and booklet.
  - Map of Upper St. John Valley (Box 2, Folder 38)
    Prepared by National Park Service. 5 copies.
  - Marshall, Howard (University of Missouri) (Box 2, Folder 39)
    Letters to and from; other documents. 43 pp. and newsletter.
  - Martin, John L. (Maine House of Representatives) (Box 2, Folder 40)
    Letters to and from. 19 pp.
  - Master Contact List, arranged in alphabetical order (Box 2, Folder 41)
    Prepared by Lisa Ornstein. 27 pp.
  - Missouri, University of (Box 2, Folder 42)
    Draft of contract with American Folklife Center. 8 pp.
  - Mitchell, George (Senator) (Box 2, Folder 43)
    letter from Juris Ubans; letters to Steve Hart (Mitchell's legislative assistant) from David Taylor. 6 pp.
  - Ornstein, Lisa (Acadian Archives) (Box 2, Folder 44)
    Letters to and from; other documents. 75 pp.
  - Peskin, Sarah (National Park Service) (Box 2, Folder 45)
    Letters to and from. 39 pp.
  - Potential informants in the Upper St. John Valley (Box 2, Folder 46)
    26 pp.
  - Publicity (Box 2, Folder 47)
    Press releases and articles about the survey project. 45 pp. and five copies of Folklife Center News.
  - Resource guide (Box 2, Folder 48)
    Memo, by Camila Bryce-Laporte, concerning the contents of a resource guide she prepared for project fieldworkers; table of contents for resource guide. 9 pp.
  - Slide show (Box 2, Folder 49)
    Text of slide-illustrated program about the Acadian Cultural Survey. Prepared by David Taylor. 23 pp.
  - Trip reports (Box 2, Folder 50)
    Reports on trips to the Upper St. John Valley, Augusta, and Boston, by David Taylor. 26 pp.
  - University of Maine at Fort Kent (Box 2, Folder 51)
    Meeting on June 5, 1991, backgrounds of participants. Prepared by Lisa Ornstein. 3 pp.
  - Whitman, David (Box 2, Folder 52)
    6 pp.
  - Audio tape inventory (Box 3, Folder 53)
    Annotated list of field tapes recorded during the survey. Prepared by Camila Bryce-Laporte. 6 pp.
  - Audio tape logs, by Ray Brassieur (Box 3, Folder 54)
    MAP-RB-A001 to MAP-RB-A016. 76 pp.
  - Audio tape logs, by Lisa Ornstein (Box 3, Folder 55)
    MAP-LO-A001 to MAP-LO-A014. 84 pp.
  - Audio tape logs, by David Whitman (Box 3, Folder 56)
    MAP-DW-R001 to MAP-DW-R007. 14 pp.; MAP-DW-A001. 3pp.
  - Biographical Data Forms (Box 3, Folder 57)
    Completed forms. 19 pp.
  - Field drawings, by Ray Brassieur (Box 3, Folder 58)
    Copies of drawings, mainly of furniture and architectural features. 37 pp.
  - Field drawings, by Howard Marshall (Box 3, Folder 59)
    Copies of drawings of architectural features. 30 pp.
  - Fieldnotes, by Ray Brassieur (Box 3, Folder 60)
    72 pp.
  - Fieldnotes, by Howard Marshall (Box 3, Folder 61)
    101 pp.
  - Fieldnotes by Lisa Ornstein (Box 3, Folder 62)
    35 pp.
  - Fieldnotes, by David Whitman (Box 3, Folder 63)
    43 pp.
  - Black-and-white photo logs, Ray Brassieur (Box 3, Folder 64)
    MAP-RB-B001 to MAP-RB-B005. 6 pp.
  - Black-and-white photo logs, Howard Marshall (Box 3, Folder 65)
    MAP-HM-B001 to MAP-HM-B021. 25 pp.
  - Black-and-white photo logs, Lisa Ornstein (Box 3, Folder 66)
    MAP-LO-B001 to MAP-LO-B002. 5 pp. (Missing log for MAP-LO-B003; may not exist).
  - Black-and-white photo logs, David Whitman (Box 3, Folder 67)
    MAP-DW-B001 to MAP-DW-B069. 104 pp. (Photos MAP-DW-B060 to MAP-DW-B069 exist as only positives; negatives are missing).
  - Contact sheets, duplicates (Box 3, Folder 68)
    Three duplicate contact sheets.
  - Color-slide logs, Ray Brassieur (Box 3, Folder 69)
    MAP-RB-C001 to MAP-RB-C012. 13 pp.
  - Color-slide logs, Howard Marshall (Box 3, Folder 70)
    MAP-HM-C001 to MAP-C021. 22 pp.
  - Color-slide logs, Lisa Ornstein (Box 3, Folder 71)
    MAP-LO-C001 to MAP-LO-C002. 2 pp.
  - Color-slide logs, David Whitman (Box 3, Folder 72)
    MAP-DW-C001 to MAP-DW-C085. 109 pp.
  - Resource survey (Box 3, Folder 73)
    Questionnaire survey of cultural institutions with holdings pertaining to Acadian history and culture. Compiled by Camila Bryce-Laporte. 40 pp.
  - Acadian Cultural Committee, Madawaska (Box 4, Folder 74)
    Proposal for establishing a cultural center in Madawaska, Maine. 120 pp.
  - Acadian Village (Box 4, Folder 75)
    Booklet about the Acadian Village, Van Buren, Maine. 2 copies.
  - Beckwith, Cynthia (Box 4, Folder 76)
    "Our Lady of Lille." Echoes, Spring 1989, pp. 27-29. [Article about Notre Dame du Mont-Carmel Church in Lille, Maine] 4 pp.
  - Eagle Lake, Maine (Box 4, Folder 77)
    Data about Eagle Lake. 4 pp.
  - Family reunion booklets (Box 4, Folder 78)
    Four booklets.
  - Fort Fairfield, Maine (Box 4, Folder 79)
    "Update of Town History for Comprehensive Plan 1991." 15 pp.
  - Freeberg, Ernie (Box 4, Folder 80)
    "Voice of the Valley." Down East, Nov. 1989. [Article about Acadian singer Ida Roy] 4 pp.
  - Giguere, Madeleine (Box 4, Folder 81)
    "Language Maintenance-Speaking French at Home." Conference paper, n.d. 33 pp.
  - Konrad, Victor A., and Michael Chaney (Box 4, Folder 82)
    "Madawaska Twin Barn." Journal of Cultural Geography. 3, no. 1 (Fall/Winter 1982): 64-75. 7 pp.
  - McDonald, Sheila (Box 4, Folder 83)
    "The War After the War: Fort Kent Blockhouse, 1839-1842. Maine State Historical Society Quarterly 29, nos. 3 and 4 (Winter-Spring 1990). 13 pp.
  - Madawaska Centennial, 1869-1969 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    [Madawaska, Me.]: N.p., [1969]. Excerpts. 28 pp.
  - Madawaska Historical Society (Box 4, Folder 85)
    Madawaska Historical Society Newletter. 2, no. 10 (Feb. 1989).
  - Madawaska, Maine: data about Madawaska (Box 4, Folder 86)
    7 pp. and two copies of booklet.
  - Michaud, A.J. (Box 4, Folder 87)
    An Acadian Heritage from the St. John River Valley (Madawaska, Me.: Valley Publishing Co., n. d.). Excerpts. 13 pp.
  - Newspaper articles (Box 4, Folder 88)
    Various articles from the St. John Valley Times, Bangor Daily News., and other newspapers concerning the Acadian Festival and other events that occurred during the period of the field survey. 137 pp.
  - Paper Talks Magazine (Box 4, Folder 89)
    Seven issues (1981, 1982, 1985, 1986, 1987, 1989, 1990).
  - Programs (Box 4, Folder 90)
    Various programs from events in the St. John Valley, summer 1991.
  - St. Bruno Parish (Box 4, Folder 91)
    St. Bruno Parish, Van Buren, Maine, Sesquicentennial 1838-1988. (N.p.: N.p., [1988]).
  - Soleil Press (Box 4, Folder 92)
    Works by and About Franco-Americans.. Catalog 1990-91.
  - Van Buren, Maine (Box 4, Folder 93)
    Miscellaneous articles about Van Buren. 29 pp. and two booklets.
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 4, Folder 94)
    5 pp.
  - Published recordings notes (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Foundresses (Box 4, Folder 96)
    The Little Franciscans of Mary. Local history for children. 52 pp.
  - Fort Kent Centennial 1869-1969 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    160 pp. + 4 pp. covers.
  - Fort Kent Historical Society 1989 Calendar (Box 4, Folder 98)
    28 pp.
  - Manuscript: Fort Kent (Box 4, Folder 99)
    Loose-leaf manuscript and draft of a book on the history and life at Fort Kent by the First National Bank. 38 pp.
  - Brassieur, C. Ray, coord. (Box 5, Folder 100)
    "The Maine Acadian Cultural Survey." 199 pp. [Draft report submitted to the National Park Service by the American Folklife Center]
  - North Atlantic Region, National Park Service (Box 5, Folder 101)
    Acadian Culture in Maine (Boston: National Park Service, 1992). 2 copies. [Draft report based on the American Folklife Center's report "The Maine Acadian Cultural Survey."]
  - North Atlantic Region, National Park Service (Box 5, Folder 102)
    Implementing the Maine Acadian Culture Preservation Act: Draft Conceptual Framework/Environmental Assessment. Revised Edition to Acadian Culture in Maine. June 1994.
  - Flag and recipe book (Box 6)
    Flag: Acadia flag: 6-3/4"x10" nylon flag on 15" plastic staff. Reunion Families' Favorite Recipes; 172 pp.
  - Resource Guide (Boxes 19-20)
    "Maine Acadian Resource Guide": compilation of various articles and other materials about the history, culture, and economy of the Upper Saint John Valley. Prepared by Camila Bryce-Laporte. Stored in two loose-leaf binders.
  - Electronic media (Box 21)
    Twenty-four 3-and-a-half-inch discs in 4 containers. 18 floppy discs in 2 containers. Most contents of discs most likely were printed and stored with the collection.
- Series 2: Sound recordings
  - Barn dance at Daigle House, Clair, New Brunswick, June 29, 1991, AFC 1991/029: DW-A001; RYN 4353; 1 audiocassette, 60 min.
    DW-A001: Musicians include Nicolo Gagne, spoon player; Pat Albert, fiddle; Roger St. Onge, accordion; Norman Oakes, guitar; Gerald Lavoie, guitar and vocal; Monique Rossignol, guitar and vocal.
  - Multi-choir concert, Good Shepherd Sisters' Centennial Celebration, St. Bruno's Catholic Church, Van Buren, Maine, part 1-3, June 21, 1991, AFC 1991/029: DW-R001 - R003; RXA 2901 - RXA 2903; 3 audiotape reels, 7 in.
    DW-R001: Performers include Annick Gagnon, St. Thomas Aquinas Church and the St. Leonard Choir; DW-R002: Paroisse St. Henri Choir, Assumption Parish Choir and the Drummond Choir; DW-R003: St. Bruno Catholic Church Choir and Sara Mae Stewart.
  - Les violons d'Acadie, Acadian Festival, Multi-Purpose Center, Madawaska, Maine, part 1-4, June 28, 1991, AFC 1991/029: DW-R004 - A007; RXA 2904 - RXA 2907; 4 audiotape reels, 7 in.
    DW-R004: Performers include Arcade Richard, Leo LeBlanc, Gordon Pelletier, Roderick, Pelletier, Bobby Kelly and Jerry and the Wanderers; DW-R005: Jerry and the Wanderers, Louis Werta, Les Garcons Ouellette, Jerry Voisine Nancy Dubay and Gerald Roy; DW-R006: Yvon Francoeure, Ouellette Family, Madame Ouellettee, Jerry Voisine and Jerry and the Wanderers; DW-R007: Robert Cormier, Beaulieu, Jerry and the Wanderers, Sam Oakes and Jerry Voisine.
  - Class session: Cultural diversity in Maine education, University of Maine at Fort Kent, Fort Kent, Maine, part 1-3, June 18, 1991, AFC 1991/029: CO-A001 - A003; RYN 4354 - RYN 4356; 3 audiocassettes, 60 min.
    CO-A001 - A003: Performers include Guy Dubay, Yvon Labbe and David Veilleux.
  - Sisters of the Good Shepherd Centennial Concert, Saint Bruno Church, Van Buren, Maine, part 1-2, June 21, 1991, AFC 1991/029: CO-A004 - A005; RYN 4357 - RYN 4358; 2 audiocassettes, 60 min.
    CO-A004: Good Shephard Sisters, Thomas Hebert, Saint Gerard Parish Choir, Paroisse Assomption Choir and Phyllis Doucette and Saint Thomas Aquinas Church Choir; CO-R005: Paroisse de Saint-Andre Choir, Jason J. Parent, Phyllis Doucelle, Assumption Parish Choir and Paroisse St. Michel Choir.
  - Red Cross Benefit for Allagash, Maine, Fort Kent Community High School, Fort Kent, Maine, part 1-3, June 22, 1991, AFC 1991/029: CO-A006 - A008; RYN 4359 - RYN 4361; 3 audiocassettes, 60 min.
    CO-A006: Carissa Dumont, Don Cyr, Sylvie Martin, Larry Davis, Dave Mallet and Charles E. Closser; CO-A007: Victoria Dance Studio, Allagash Little People (Allagash, Maine), Pat Pelletier, Dave Pelletier, Brenda Hebert, Reckless Entertainers; A008: Guy Kelly Jr., Dale Connors, Gallagher Brothers, Ken Gilman, Patrick J. Gallagher and Donald Gallagher.
  - Acadian Mass, Saint David Church, Saint David, Maine, June 27, 1991, AFC 1991/029: CO-A009; RYN 4362; 1 audiocassette, 60 min.
    CO-A009: Monseigneur Chalut and Saint David Church Choir.
  - Story of the Acadians: Presentations by Bernette Albert and Rosaire Sirois, Madawaska High School, Madawaska, Maine, part 1-2, June 28, 1991, AFC 1991/029: CO-A010 - A11; RYN 4363 - RYN 4364; 2 audiocassettes, 60 min.
    CO-A010: Bernette Albert, Rosaire Sirois; CO-A11: Rosaire Sirois.
  - Les violons d'Acadie, Multi-Purpose Center, Madawaska, Maine, June 28, 1991, AFC 1991/029: CO-A012; RYN 4365; 1 audiocassette, 60 min.
    CO-A012: Paul Leblanc, Arcade Richard, Gordon Pelletier, Bobby Kelly, Jerry and the Wanderers and Jerry Voisine.
  - Singing by Connie Morin Desrosier, St. Agatha, Maine, July 08, 1991, AFC 1991/029: CO-A013; RYN 4366; 1 audiocassette, 60 min.
    CO-A013: Desrosier, Connie Morin.
  - Singing and storytelling by Ida Bourgoin Roy, Van Buren, Maine, July 10, 1991, AFC 1991/029: CO-A014; RYN 4367; 1 audiocassette, 60 min.
    CO-A014: Ida Bourgoin Roy.
  - Performance by the Poor, Poor Woodsman Band, Fort Kent Hotel, Fort Kent, Maine, June 08, 1991, AFC 1991/029: RB-A001; RYN 4368; 1 audiocassette, 60 min.
    RB-A001: Poor, Poor Woodsman Band, Harold Jackson, Sam Oakes, Nelson Michaud and Maurice Michaud.
  - Music party and barbecue at Sam Oakes' home, Fort Kent, Maine, June 09, 1991, AFC 1991/029: RB-A002; RYN 4369; 1 audiocassette, 60 min.
    RB-A002: Sam Oakes and Merrill Oakes.
  - Interview with Herman Deprey and family, New Canada, Maine, part 1-3, June 12, 1991, AFC 1991/029: RB-A003 - A005; RYN 4370 - RYN 4372; 3 audiocassettes, 60 min.
    RB-A003: Interview with Herman Deprey, Darcey Deprey and Danny Deprey; RB-A004 - RBA005: Interview with Herman Deprey, Magloire (Mac) Deprey and Blanche Deprey.
  - Tour of the study area with Pat Ouellette and Julie Bayley, various locations, Maine, part 1-2, June 17, 1991, AFC 1991/029: RB-A006 - A007; RYN 4373 - RYN 4374; 2 audiocassettes, 60 min.